<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Algorithm - Category - MartinLwx&#39;s blog</title>
        <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/categories/algorithm/</link>
        <description>Algorithm - Category - MartinLwx&#39;s blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>martinlwx@163.com (MartinLwx)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>martinlwx@163.com (MartinLwx)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 12:30:31 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martinlwx.github.io/en/categories/algorithm/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Solving DP problems by SRTBOT Framework</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/solving-dynamic-programming-problems-using-srtbot/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 12:30:31 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>MartinLwx</author>
    <guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/solving-dynamic-programming-problems-using-srtbot/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Intro When solving algorithm problems, what often gives me a headache are dynamic programming problems(DP problems). They are the type of problems that I can&rsquo;t figure out on my own after thinking for a long time, but after seeing the answer, it suddenly becomes clear and reasonable. However, the next time I encounter a similar problem, I may forget how to solve it. I have also read many people&rsquo;s solutions and tried to digest and apply their ideas, but I have been unable to find a particularly good framework that works for all dynamic programming problems.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Boyer-Moore Majority Voting Algorithm Explained</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/boyer-moore-majority-voting-algorithm-explained/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 18:15:19 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>MartinLwx</author>
    <guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/boyer-moore-majority-voting-algorithm-explained/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Intro Today I coded the Leetcode 169. Majority Element again. I vaguely remember what the optimal solution is called Boyer-Moore Majority Voting Algorithm. However, I have no idea what is except for its name. So I plan to systematically learn the principle of this algorithm and summarize it to write this blog. I once heard that:
If you want to master something, teach it :)
So, I&rsquo;m here today to share this algorithm with you, and try to teach you this method in plain language, so let&rsquo;s get started :)]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
