<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Python - Category - MartinLwx&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/categories/python/</link>
        <description>Python - Category - MartinLwx&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>martinlwx@163.com (MartinLwx)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>martinlwx@163.com (MartinLwx)</webMaster><copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license noopener&#34; href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC-ND 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 16:18:02 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martinlwx.github.io/en/categories/python/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Type hints: what and why</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/type-hints-in-python/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 16:18:02 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>
        <name>MartinLwx</name>
    </author><guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/type-hints-in-python/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[IntroI was immediately drawn to Python when I first encountered it due to its dynamic language features. Python use the &ldquo;duck typing&rdquo; design, which means that the type of an object is not as important as its behavior. This feature allows for faster development and a reduction in burdensome type declarations. Additionally, the support of powerful third-party libraries solidifies Python as my preferred programming language.😺
However, with the proposal of PEP 4841, Python decided to introduce type hints, which seem to be in line with statically typed languages.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Unpacking in Python 3.5</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/unpacking-in-python/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 23:16:30 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>
        <name>MartinLwx</name>
    </author><guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/unpacking-in-python/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This post is originally written in jupyter notebook and then convert to markdown. To get the original notebook files. Please check the repo
IntroToday I want to talk about the unpacking operators(* and **) in python.
Basic usageWe use * for numeric data types to indicate we want to do multiplication. However, we can also apply * to iterable objects1, which means we want to unpack all the elements inside them.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>The f-strings in Python 3.6</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/f-strings-in-python/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 22:15:03 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>
        <name>MartinLwx</name>
    </author><guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/f-strings-in-python/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This post is originally written in jupyter notebook and then convert to markdown. To get the original notebook files. Please check the repo
IntroString formatting can be regarded as one of the most common activities in daily programming. We often need to output various strings and precisely control their format.
In some outdated Python tutorials, you may see the use of % to format strings. However, after Python 3.6, f-strings have become the optimal choice for formatting strings.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Walrus Operator in Python 3.8</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/walrus-operator-in-python/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 23:36:12 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>
        <name>MartinLwx</name>
    </author><guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/walrus-operator-in-python/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This post is originally written in jupyter notebook and then convert to markdown. To get the original notebook files. Please check the repo
IntroToday I’m going to talk about a new feature introduced in Python 3.8: the Walrus operator（:=）, which is a much-debated feature, but it’s finally passed and released 🤔
In Python, an assignment statement (=) is not an expression but a statement. Walrus operator is expression though. The difference between statement and expression can be simply understood as: expression always returns a value, while statement does not return a value.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Pattern Matching in Python 3.10</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/pattern-matching-in-python/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 15:14:57 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>
        <name>MartinLwx</name>
    </author><guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/pattern-matching-in-python/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This post is originally written in jupyter notebook and then convert to markdown. To get the original notebook files. Please check the repo
IntroToday I want to talk about the new feature bring in Python 3.10 &ndash; Pattern matching 🎉
Those who have learned C language must be familiar with the following switch statement:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 switch (expression) { case constant_1: // statements break; case constant_2: // statements break; // Fall through // the value of the expression can be either constant_3 or constant_4 :) case constant_3: case constant_4: // statements default: // default statements } To recap, the syntax rules of the switch statement:]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How to Use Logging in Python</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/how-to-use-logging-in-python/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 23:32:50 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>
        <name>MartinLwx</name>
    </author><guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/how-to-use-logging-in-python/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Intro Recently I was fine-tuning my deep learning model, and I habitually started to use print to print some key information on the terminal. So my workflow is like:
I type some hyperparameters to train my model. I manually opened an Excel to record the hyperparameters used and the model evaluation results. And I will go back to step 1. If I am not satisfied with results. Soon, I became bored with this workflow (In fact, I kept this for quite a long time.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>How to draw a simple relation graph in Python</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/how-to-draw-a-simple-relation-graph-in-python/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 10:21:15 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>
        <name>MartinLwx</name>
    </author><guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/how-to-draw-a-simple-relation-graph-in-python/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Intro The process of drawing a simple relation graph in python can be broken down into 2 steps.
Define a graph. Draw a graph. Step 1. Define a graph In this step, we will use the networkx package.
Install tutorialIf you are using conda, you can just type conda install networkx
If you are using pip, you can just type pip install networkx
NodesFirst of all, you need to create a graph.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
