<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>ML-DL - Category - MartinLwx&#39;s blog</title>
        <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/categories/ml-dl/</link>
        <description>ML-DL - Category - MartinLwx&#39;s blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>martinlwx@163.com (MartinLwx)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>martinlwx@163.com (MartinLwx)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 13:45:48 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martinlwx.github.io/en/categories/ml-dl/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>How to understand the backpropagation algorithm</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/backpropagation-tutorial/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 13:45:48 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>MartinLwx</author>
    <guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/backpropagation-tutorial/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Intro In the field of deep learning, optimizing the network involves a crucial process of continuously updating the weights and bias items. This is achieved by implementing the gradient descent method, which progressively minimizes the loss function. At the heart of this process lies the backpropagation algorithm, which facilitates efficient computation of gradients across the network
To better understand this concept, let us recall the formula for gradient descent. In this formula, we utilize the symbol $\theta$ to represent all the learnable parameters of the model, $J$ to represent the cost or loss function, and $\alpha$ to denote the learning rate.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Linear Regression Model Guide - theory part</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/linear-regression-model-guide-theory/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 12:37:52 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>MartinLwx</author>
    <guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/linear-regression-model-guide-theory/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction Recently, I review the machine learning course of Andrew ng in Coursera. Surprisingly, I can still learn a lot, so I decided to write some postsðŸ‘.
To talk about linear regression, we must first have a basic understanding of what is machine learning. What is machine learning? abstractly speaking, machine learning is learning a function: $$ f(input) = output $$ where $f$ refers to the specific machine learning model. Machine learning is a methodology for automatically mining the relationship between input and output.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
