<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>ML-DL - Category - MartinLwx&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/categories/ml-dl/</link>
        <description>ML-DL - Category - MartinLwx&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>martinlwx@163.com (MartinLwx)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>martinlwx@163.com (MartinLwx)</webMaster><copyright>&lt;a rel=&#34;license noopener&#34; href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC-ND 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 18:29:31 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://martinlwx.github.io/en/categories/ml-dl/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>LLM inference optimization - KV Cache</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/llm-inference-optimization-kv-cache/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 18:29:31 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>martinlwx@163.com (MartinLwx)</author><guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/llm-inference-optimization-kv-cache/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Background The secret behind LLM is that it will generate tokens one by one based on all the previous tokens.
Let&rsquo;s assume that we have already generated $t$ tokens, denoted by $x_{1:t}$. In the next iteration, the LLM will generate $x_{1:t+1}$. Note that the first $t$ tokens are the same.
$$x_{1:t+1}=\text{LLM}(x_{1:t})$$
The next iteration is similar.
$$x_{1:t+2}=\text{LLM}(x_{1:t+1})$$
In summary, in each iteration, we will use the output of the previous round as a new input for the LLM.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>LoRA fine-tuning</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/lora-finetuning/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 22:57:06 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>martinlwx@163.com (MartinLwx)</author><guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/lora-finetuning/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What&rsquo;s LoRA Since the era of LLM(large language model) arrived, fine-tuning LLM has become a challenge because the LLM models are extremely large, making it difficult to perform full fine-tuning. There are mainly two approaches: freeze the entire LLM and perform prompt tuning or In-context Learning; freeze the entire LLM but inserting trainable modules. Today, I will introduce the LoRA(Low-Rank Adaptation), which corresponds to the latter technical approach. This is a work proposed by the Microsoft team1]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A trick to calculating partial derivatives in machine learning</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/a-trick-to-calculating-partial-derivatives-in-ml/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:31:50 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>martinlwx@163.com (MartinLwx)</author><guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/a-trick-to-calculating-partial-derivatives-in-ml/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Intro You may have difficulties when trying to calculate the partial derivatives in machine learning like me. Even though I found a good reference cookbook that could be used to derive the gradients, I still got confused. Today, I want to share a practical technique I recently learned from this video: when calculating partial derivatives in machine learning, you can treat everything as if it were a scalar and then make the shapes match]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Demystifying Pytorch&#39;s Strides Format</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/how-to-reprensent-a-tensor-or-ndarray/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 15:22:02 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>martinlwx@163.com (MartinLwx)</author><guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/how-to-reprensent-a-tensor-or-ndarray/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Intro Even though I have been using Numpy and Pytorch for a long time, I never really knew how they implemented the underlying tensors and why they are so efficient. Recently, while studying the course Deep Learning Systems, I finally got the opportunity to try implementing tensors on my own. After going through the process, my understanding of tensors is much better ðŸ§
As a Pytorch user, is it necessary to understand the underlying tensor storage mechanism?]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to understand the backpropagation algorithm</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/backpropagation-tutorial/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 13:45:48 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>martinlwx@163.com (MartinLwx)</author><guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/backpropagation-tutorial/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Update: Backpropagation in matrix form could be found here
Intro In the field of deep learning, optimizing the network involves a crucial process of continuously updating the weights and bias items. This is achieved by implementing the gradient descent method, which progressively minimizes the loss function. At the heart of this process lies the backpropagation algorithm, which facilitates efficient computation of gradients across the network
To better understand this concept, let us recall the formula for gradient descent.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Linear Regression Model Guide - theory part</title>
    <link>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/linear-regression-model-guide-theory/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 12:37:52 &#43;0800</pubDate><author>martinlwx@163.com (MartinLwx)</author><guid>https://martinlwx.github.io/en/linear-regression-model-guide-theory/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction Recently, I review the machine learning course of Andrew ng in Coursera. Surprisingly, I can still learn a lot, so I decided to write some postsðŸ‘.
To talk about linear regression, we must first have a basic understanding of what is machine learning. What is machine learning? abstractly speaking, machine learning is learning a function: $$ f(input) = output $$ where $f$ refers to the specific machine learning model. Machine learning is a methodology for automatically mining the relationship between input and output.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
